♪ We wish you a Merry Christmas ♪
♪ And a happy New Year
♪ And a happy New Year ♪
♪ Good tidings we bring...
♪ Good tidings we bring... ♪
Don't be shy, we have plenty for everyone.
不要客气 我们有足够食物
Santa's here till noon, so take your time.
圣诞老人会一直停留到中午 所以大家可以慢慢来
Make way, make way.Hey.
-让开 让开 -嗨
Back again, Vicious?
Vicious 你又来了
That's Mr. Vicious to you, lady.
女士 对你而言 我是Vicious先生
Got any milk back there?
后面有牛奶吗
You are not here for milk; we all know why you are here.
你才不是来这儿要牛奶的 我们都知道你为什么在这儿
Yeah? Well, call a cop.
是吗 那你报警啊
I can't believe I need a bouncer on the food line.
我无法相信在领取食物这边竟然会需要保安
-嗨 Jerome去哪儿了 -我猜他出去扔垃圾了
Hey, where's Jerome?I think he's taking out the garbage.
Jerome?!
Jerome
Jerome!
We need our peacekeeper.
我们需要我们的和平保卫员
Seems like our friend Vicious
看来我们的朋友Vicious
并没有领会到昨天的信息 而且你貌似
didn't get the message yesterday, and since you're
the only one he will listen to, could you just...?
是唯一能说服他的人 你是否可以
Oh, God. Jerome?
噢 天啊 Jerome
[breathless]: Oh, God.
噢 天啊
♪
All right, final report's almost done.
好啦 最后一份报告基本上搞定了
那个证人名单怎么样了
How's that witness list coming along?
I am sending it to you right now.
我这就把它发送给你
Nick 我们的供词总结怎么样了
How's our confession summary, Nick?
I'm pressing "print" in three, two, one.
我正在按打印键 3 2 1
啊 节日前最后一个案子发出的美妙的声音
Ah, the sweet sound of the last case before the holidays.
Jack 请不要诅咒我们
Jack, please, do not jinx us.
If anyone needs me, I'll either be on the slopes
如果有人需要我 我要么在滑雪坡道上
or drinking some damn fine whiskey in the lodge.
要么在小木屋里喝着非常棒的威士忌酒
Christmas in Vermont, lucky you.
在Vermont过圣诞 你真幸运
-你明天开车过去吗 -清晨就出发
You driving up tomorrow?Crack of dawn.
然而我连行李都还没有打包好
And I'm not even close to being packed.
无论如何 大家圣诞节快乐
Anyway, Merry, Merry Christmas, all.TORRES: Hey, you, too.
嗨 你也是
-圣诞快乐 -如果我也能开车就好了
Merry Christmas.BISHOP: Sure wish I could drive.
I just hate flying on Christmas Eve.
我就是讨厌在平安夜飞行
Yeah. You and me both. Oklahoma bound?
没错 我也是 你是有俄克拉荷马州的牵挂吗
Mom has been baking all week. You?
我妈都准备了一周的烘焙点心了 你呢
Chicago with the in-laws.
和岳父岳母一家在芝加哥
Delilah带着双胞胎们在光明节的时候就过去了
【注：光明节是犹太教的节日】
Delilah's had the twins there since Hanukkah.
我们已经聊了两个星期了
We're talking two whole weeks.
我相信你并不介意 呃 离开孩子们一点时间吧
I'm sure you didn't mind, uh, a little break from the kids.
第一天一切都是美好的安静的
Well, the first day was nice and quiet,
但是第二天起觉得好像太安静了点
but every day since then is a little too quiet.
You'll know what I mean someday.
未来的某一天那你会明白我的意思的
Yeah, no.
呵呵 不会的
和Palmer家的孩子在圣诞晚餐后
Playing Candyland with, uh, Palmer's kid
玩儿糖果世界
after Christmas, uh, dinner, that's, uh,
plenty of parenting for me. [chuckles]
对我而言就是足够的养育时间了
I just love that Jimmy's having you over.
我很高兴Jimmy愿意邀请你过去
Aw, I just love that you make it sound like a,
噢 我很高兴你让这个听上去
like a charity case. Ugh.
像是一个慈善行为
Okay.
好吧
Last bit of paperwork. Donzo.
最后一点点书面工作 搞定
好啦 伙计们 第一轮蛋奶酒就由这个人出啦
All right, guys. First round of eggnog is on this guy.
Ooh, count me in.
噢 算我一份
哇哦 我以为你现在应该
Whoa. I thought you were supposed
to be in New York by now.
都抵达纽约了呢
改变计划了 我妈和我妹妹决定
Change of plans. My mom and sister decided
去坐游轮 所以我决定
to go on a cruise, so I decided
留在这儿把活儿给补上
to stay here and catch up on work.
Hey. No one should be working on Christmas.
没有人应该在圣诞节工作
是啊 没有人应该在工作日的正午之前
Yeah, and no one should be making eggnog plans
做出蛋奶酒计划
before noon on a workday.
You're so worried about jinxing, McGee.
McGee 你是那么的担心厄运吗?
TORRES: Yeah. Relax, McGee.
是啊 McGee 放松
这是一个众所周知的事实
Listen, it's a known fact,
在假日期间 犯罪率都会降低
the crime rate goes down during holiday time.
事实上 真相恰好相反
Actually, the exact opposite is true.
-但是人要有梦想 -伙计们 相信我
But one can dream.TORRES: Guys, trust me.
是蛋奶酒的时间了 我们搞定了
Okay? It's eggnog time. We are donzo.
GIBBS: No, we're not.
不 我们并没有
Dead Navy vet in Columbia Heights.
在哥伦比亚海茨地区有一具海军老兵的尸体
【注:位于明尼苏达州】
Uh, Navy veteran, boss?
呃 老大 海军老兵吗
这不一定是我们的管辖范围
That's not always our jurisdiction.
但是今天它是了
Well, it is today.
MPD is slammed.
明尼苏达警方已经忙不过来了
好吧 希望 这是一个简洁明了的案子
Hmm. Well, hopefully, it is an open-and-shut case.
Ah!ALL: Don't jinx us.
-啊 -不要乱立Flag
天啊
Geez...
Jerome的纹身让我想起他曾经服役过
NEERA: Jerome's tattoo reminded me of his service.
觉得应该给你们打电话
It just seemed right to call you guys.
Big dude.
人很高大
他是一个大号的泰迪熊
NEERA: He was a big teddy bear.
很大的刀口
Big knife wounds.
他在这儿工作多久了
How long had he worked here?
About three years,
差不多3年了
但完全是一个志愿者
but strictly as a volunteer.
我们的预算没办法再给守护天使支付报酬
Budget didn't cover guardian angels.
对于众人而言 他就是守护天使
That's what he was... to everyone.
老大 在后面的暴雨下水道里找到这把刀
Boss, found this knife tossed in a storm drain back there.
可能是作案凶器
Could be the murder weapon.
那我们现在就需要一个嫌疑犯了
Oh, well, all we need now is a suspect.
-Jerome有敌人吗 -不 没有
Jerome had enemies?No, none.
我的意思是 除了那些他一直挡在外头的
I mean, except for the neighborhood drug dealers
社区里的毒贩们
he was always trying to keep out of here.
你知道吗 现在想起来
You know, come to think of it,
他们中的一员在昨天被Jerome给扔出去后
one of them was back again just this morning
今天早上又来了
after Jerome had tossed him out yesterday.
那个家伙 他们称为 Vicious
A-a guy they call "Vicious."
马上去找
On it.
在Jerome克服了PTSD 酗酒
NEERA: After everything Jerome had overcome--
这一切后
PTSD, alcohol.
他在本地的退役军人事务处都得到了一个床位
He even got himself a bed at the local V.A.
然而现在却这样了
And... now this.
你找到什么信息了吗 McGee
Hey. You got anything, McGee?
One second.
等一下
还在上传中
It's still loading.
搞定 找到了 在这里
All right, there we go. Here it is.
街头名号 Vicious 真名 Albert Leary
Street name "Vicious," real name Albert Leary.
他有一个很长的犯罪记录 最后的已知地址
He's got a long rap sheet and a last known address
离这里不远
not far from here.
那就是他 那个就是Vicious
NEERA: That's him. Th-That's Vicious.
Bishop Torres 你们跟着我
Bishop, Torres, you're with me.
McGee 去那个Jerome住宿的退役军人事务中心
McGee, the V.A. center where Jerome was staying,
看看你能发现什么
see what you can find.
Let me get you the address.
我把地址给你
嗨 不用担心 伙计们 我没问题的
Hey, don't worry about it, guys, I got this.
我现在告诉你们
VICIOUS: I'm telling you now.
如果没有搜查令 谁都不允许进来
Ain't nobody coming in here without a warrant.
他们为什么叫你Vicious
Why do they call you Vicious?
宝贝 我也希望我知道
Yeah. I wish I knew, baby.
你正看着一个守法公民
You're looking at a law-abiding citizen.
也许是因为你是一个恶毒的骗子
Maybe it's because you're a vicious liar.
我没有撒谎 亲爱的 我和Jerome那天
I ain't lying, mijo. Me and Jerome maybe had
也许有一些小误会
a little misunderstanding the other day,
但是我没有杀任何人
but I ain't never killed nobody.
-他是不是 - 嗯哼
Did he just...?Mm-hmm.
你刚刚是不是叫我 亲爱的
Did you just call me "mijo"?
是啊 就像你刚刚说我是一个骗子
Yeah, and you just called me a liar.
如果你们不介意 我还有别的事情要做
Now if you don't mind, I got things to do.
We mind.
我们介意的
把你的脚从我的门边挪开
Get your foot up out of my door, man.
把你的门从我的脚边挪开
Get your door off my foot.
[grunts]
我们有一些问题
We have some questions.
好吧 管他呢 进来吧
Fine. Hell with it. Come on in.
看到了吗 我什么都没有
See? I got nothing.
但是我仍然要打电话给我的律师去起诉你们
But I'm still calling my lawyer to sue your asses,
因为我知道我的权利
'cause I know my damn rights.
是啊 既然他们已经给你说过
Yeah, one would hope so since you've
那么多次了 希望你记住了
had them read to you so many times.
Damn.
该死的
如果你没有杀Jerome
GIBBS: If you didn't kill Jerome,
你今天早上在流浪人员的避难所干什么
what were you doing at the homeless shelter this morning?
取早餐 这是犯罪行为吗
Getting breakfast. That a crime?
你看上去并不不是流浪人员
You don't look very homeless.
嗨 律师 我这儿有一个问题
Hey, yo, law man, I got a problem here.
这个门后面是什么
What's behind that door?
嗨 我说了你可以进来
Hey. I said you could come in here.
但是门后和你没有任何关系
Back there ain't none of your business.
是吗 那我们就有问题了
Yeah. Here's the issue, though.
当你说和我没有关系的时候
When you say that's none of my business,
这就和我有关系了
it kind of makes it my business.
哇哦
Ooh.
我说了 不要进去
I said don't go back there.
Easy, buddy.Oh, yeah, now you say easy.
-放松点 伙计 -噢 你现在说放松点了
I told you I didn't want you in here.
我告诉了你 我不希望你进来
Now, get out!A little late for that.
-现在给我出去 -现在说这个有点晚了呢
Let's put the gun down before this gets any worse.
在事态恶化前 我们先把枪放下
Put yours down!
你们把枪放下
Bishop, you okay?
Bishop 你还好吗
Yeah. Yeah, yeah.
是的 没事 没事
Look-look at me. Okay.
-看着 看着我 -好的
Are you all right?Yeah. I'm okay.
-你还好吗 -是的 我没事
TORRES: He's dead.[rattling]
他死了
Okay? Yeah.
-真的没事 -没事
Ready?
准备好了吗
[baby crying]Uh...
呃
Vicious is a dad.
Vicious 是个做了爸爸的人
真不是个开始假期的好方式 Gibbs
Hardly any way to kick off the holidays, Gibbs.
本年度最轻描淡写的说法了吧
Understatement of the year.
And Bishop is all right?
Bishop没事吧
Yeah. Considering.
是的 相对来说没事
她和Torres把孩子带到了儿童服务机构
She and Torres took the kid to Child Services.
但愿他们能找到孩子的母亲
Well, hopefully, they can locate the baby's mother.McGEE: Hey, boss.
嘿 老大
看起来我错过了一场严重的枪战 主任
Guess I missed some pretty serious fireworks. Director.
为什么 McGee 你当时在哪里
Why, McGee, where were you?
I was at the, uh, V.A. center,
我那时在 那个 老兵援助中心
整理我们受害者的私人物品
collecting our victim's personal effects.
没有明显的线索 但看情况我们也不需要了
No obvious leads, but sounds like we don't need them.
Bishop和Torres似乎很确定这个叫Vicious的
Bishop and Torres seem pretty certain
-是我们要找的凶手 -他们联系你了
this Vicious guy is our killer.They called you?
不 他们 呃 在楼下大厅里
No, they're, uh, down in the lobby.
他们为什么不和你一起上来
Why didn't they come up with you?
他们在忙得手忙脚乱的
Well, they kind of have their hands full.
Full with what?
忙什么
Ah, Gibbs, Director, hey.
啊 Gibbs 主任 嘿
我们能解释的
[quietly]: We can explain.
儿童服务机构那里发生什么事了
What happened to Child Services?
嘘 他在睡觉
Shh. He's sleeping.
就是当我们堵在路上的时候我打他们的电话
TORRES: So we were sitting in traffic and I called them,
大概打了五次但他们每次都让我等着 一次又一次的等着
like, five times and they put me on hold every time, like, over and over.
Yeah. They must must be really overwhelmed this time of year.
对 他们每年到这个时候应该都是忙得不可开交的
You know, so between that and the traffic on the Beltway...
你懂的 所以考虑到这个以及特区的交通情况
TORRES: Yeah, so we figure, bring the baby over here.
对 所以我们想着 把孩子带到这里来
We can find the mother way faster than Child Services.
我们找到孩子母亲的速度要比儿童服务机构快得多
And once we find her, we will have closed the case on Vicious,
当我们找到她的时候 我们就能了结Vicious的案子
and we can all go home for Christmas.
然后我们就都能回家过圣诞了
Oh, that kind of rhymes.
哦 听着还有些押韵
So Bishop nearly gets killed
所以Bishop差点被杀
and they both went into shock?
而且他们俩都受什么刺激了
No, uh, Director.
不 那个 主任
This office is no place for a baby.
这个办公室可不是婴儿呆的地方
Though he is pretty damn cute.
虽然这孩子是非常的可爱
Cool. So, uh, we're good?
说得对 所以 我们没事了
不 我们可不是没事
No. We are not good.
We are not near good.
我们的事还多着呢
But here we are.
但我们到这步了
这个孩子现在是你们的职责了
That baby is your responsibility.
McGee 你试试看能不能
McGee, see if you can unlock
解锁这个变态的手机
this creep's cell phone,
找找里面有没有孩子母亲的相关信息
and see if the mother's in there somewhere.
他的记录里面没有关于他的婚姻状况或者孩子的
Nothing in his records about marital status or kids.
You two, go down and check with Kasie.
你们两个 下楼去Kasie那里看看
She's running prints off the knife we found.
她在查找我们发现的那把刀上的指纹
让她同时也查一下这个孩子的DNA
Tell her to run the baby's DNA while she's at it.
You got it, Gibbs.McGEE: Uh, boss,
-这就去办 老大 -呃 老大
有个人自称是Albert Leary的律师
someone claiming to be Albert Leary's attorney
-想见见他的委托人 -Vicious
wants to see his client.Vicious.
[sighs]
Any prints from our suspect yet?
提取到我们的嫌犯的指纹了吗
我才刚打开他的裹尸袋
I'm only just unwrapping him now.
好吧 那么这位肯定是我们的受害人了
Okay. Well, then this must be our victim.
是的 一个无家可归的越战老兵
Yeah. He is a homeless vet.
很明显是庇护所里的真英雄
Apparently a real hero down at the shelter.
Um...
嗯
Jerome Murray
Jerome Murray.
Wow.
哇
Wow, what?
哇 什么
You know him?
你认识他吗
只是 让我想起了某个人
Just, uh, reminded me of someone.
Yeah? Who?
是吗 谁
TORRES: Oh, good.
哦 太好了
Kasie, you're here.
Kasie你在这里
Oh. Here I am. Is that a baby?
对 我在这儿 这是个婴儿吗
呃 对的 对的 没错 他是不会进来的
Uh, yes. Yes, it is, and he is not coming in.
呃 孩子 就是说 这个人的孩子
Uh, baby, as in, like, this guy's baby?
I heard you found one at his place.
我听说你在他的住处发现了一个
Uh, hey. We need his DNA ASAP
呃 嘿 我们需要尽快获取他的DNA
以及你在刀上找到的任何指纹
and whatever prints you found on the knife.
Oh, yeah. No problem. What's the hurry?
哦 好的 没问题 为什么这么着急
The hurry is Christmas.
急着过圣诞
我们只需要找到这个孩子的妈妈
BISHOP: Well, we just need to find the baby's mother,
并且确定Vicious就是凶手
and confirm that Vicious was the killer,
最好是在我们明天离开之前
preferably before we leave tomorrow.
噢 他是最可爱的了 他叫什么名字
Oh, he is the cutest; what's his name?
Well, we didn't get the chance to ask,
我们没有问名字的机会
with the shooting and all.
因为枪战等等
也是 我听说了
Right. I heard about that.
I'm so glad you're okay.
你没事我真是太高兴了
Thanks.
谢谢
你会给我血液样本和指纹的吧
You'll send me blood and prints?
Quick as I can.
我会尽快做的
I admit, Agent Gibbs, to a rather reluctant soft spot
我承认 Gibbs探员 我对这位要援助的客户
for my pro bono clients, which is why I'm here.
实在是放心不下 所以就来这里了
Ah, so you're the one he called.
啊 原来他联系的人是你
Yes, and I hadn't seen nor spoken
对 而且自从我几个月前帮他得到了
to Albert since getting him a plea deal months ago.
辩诉交易之后我就没再见过他或者跟他说过话
Then out of the blue this phone call and those gunshots.
然后突然间这个手机响了还伴随着枪声
I went by his place and the local P.D. pointed me here.
我去了他的住处 当地警方让我到这里来
Well, what can we do for you?
那么我们能为你做些什么呢
I saw the blood.
我看到血迹了
May I ask what happened? Is he even alive?
我能问问出了什么事吗 他还活着吗
No. He was a suspect in a murder investigation.
他死了 他是一起凶杀案的嫌犯
He would not answer questions.
他不想回答问题
He started shooting.[scoffs]
先开了枪
Man, you try to help these people, and they just...
天哪 你想帮助这些人 但他们就是
won't be helped.
没救
He ever mention a wife, girlfriend?
他曾提到过妻子或者女朋友之类的吗
Oh, couldn't tell you.
噢 这个我也没法说
Soft spot or not, I maintain a healthy personal distance.
不管喜欢不喜欢 我坚守着正常的个人距离
I mean, for all I know, Albert had ten of each.
我是说 据我所知 他有不少的妻子或者女友
This one would have just had a baby. A baby?
-我们说的这位应该是刚有了个孩子 -一个孩子
[chuckles]: Oh, man. Come on.
噢 天哪 不是吧
还是那句话 让我说 他有十个孩子也不奇怪
Again... for all I know, he had ten of those, too.
Right.
没错
Okay. Sorry about your client.
好吧 为你的客户感到遗憾
Thank you.
谢谢
Oh, come to think of it,
哦 忽然想起来
Albert said that he was from Florida.
Albert说他是从佛罗里达来的
Might be a girlfriend down there.
可能在那边会有个女朋友
TORRES: There you go, buddy.
这就对了 兄弟
Good boy, Nicholas.
真是好孩子 Nicholas
Nicholas?
Nicholas
Yeah, we might as well give him a name. Hmm.
对 我们不妨给他起个名字吧
呣
So you name him after yourself?
所以你用你的名字给他起名
No, the... it's, like, NCIS.
不是 就像 NCIS
You know, you move some letters around,
你懂的 你挪动一下字母的位置
you toss in a view.Mm, yeah, right, mm-hmm.
-再随便加点 -嗯 你说是就是吧
I'd say he's more of a...
要我说他更适合叫
Logan or Cody.
Logan或者Cody
这名字简直是不能更加的白人化了
Those are, like, the whitest names ever.
Rude.
真不给面子
Well, whatever his name is,
不管他叫什么名字吧
he is adorable.
他都很惹人喜欢
Isn't he cute, McGee?
他太可爱了 不是吗 McGee
All babies are cute.
所有的宝宝都很可爱
Yet you won't even look at him.
嘴上这么说你都不肯看他一眼
是的 那是因为如果我直视他的眼睛 我就和他建立了关系
Yes. That's because if we make eye contact, I will bond,
and if I bond, I'll get distracted from this case,
如果我和他建立了关系 我就不能专心处理案子
which in turn could prevent me from spending Christmas
反过来就会影响我回家过圣诞
with my own two little cuties, so let's just find his mother.
和我自己的两个小宝贝团聚 所以我们还是找到他的妈妈吧
Okay, you're right. We got distracted.
是啊 你说得对 我们分心了
And, look, he's all asleep now,
而且你看 他现在睡着了
so... we'll be able to get some work done.
所以 我们可以搞定一些工作了
Careful. Babies do wake up.
小心点 婴儿们很容易醒来的
McGee, don't worry.
McGee 别担心
We got this.
我们能搞定的
Okay.
好吧
[baby cries]
TORRES: Whoa.
哇哦
Nicholas, buddy, what happened?
Nicholas 宝宝 怎么了
You jinxed us. Again.
你又一次咒了我们
[flatulence]
All right, somebody put a BOLO out.
好了 你们谁发布个通缉令
On who?On the 300-pound biker
-通缉谁 -一个在这孩子的尿布里
who dropped a log in this kid's diaper.
拉了一大坨的300磅的自行车手
Oh, my God.
噢 我的天哪
[sniffing]
Oh, no. TORRES: No worries.
-哦 不 -不用担心
We are prepared.
我们早有准备
[clears throat] Here, here.
看这里 看这里
Oh...We got, um...
噢 我们有
we bought plenty.
我们买了很多
Oh, no. No, these are for toddlers.
哦 不 不 这些是让幼童用的
These are way too big for him.
对他来说太大了
Hey, uh, McGee?
嘿 那个 McGee
So, like...
那么 我是说
what do we do?
我们该怎么办
What do you mean? You got this.
你什么意思 你说你能搞定的
[groans]
Jimmy.
找Jimmy去
[baby crying]Ah, come on, buddy.
啊 别闹了吧 兄弟
It's nice to know I haven't lost my touch.
很高兴知道了我还没失去手感
Yeah, cloth diapers are so much better than disposable,
布尿布比一次性尿布好得多
both for the environment and for the baby.
对环境和婴儿都好
Here, let me get that.What? No.
-让我来 -什么 不行
You can't use a stapler.
你不能用订书机
Safety pins. Even I know that.
用安全别针 连我都知道这个
Seeing as we don't have any safety pins,
由于我们没有安全别针
these little binder clips
这些小长尾夹
should do the trick.
应该可以解决问题
Palmer 你在做什么 你会夹到他的 你夹到他了
Palmer, what are you doing? You're gonna pinch him. You're pinching him.
没事的 他可能只是饿了
No, it's okay. He's probably just hungry.Oh, here,
这儿 我有他喝的奶
I have his formula.
不行 那个牌子不行
Oh, no, not that brand.
No. That's filled with, uh, preservatives, corn syrup...
里面全防腐剂 玉米糖浆
Yeah. Put that back. Maybe some apple juice.
是啊 把它放回去 来点苹果汁怎么样
那更糟糕 你顺便再给他倒杯啤酒吧
That's even worse. You might as well pour him a beer.
-哼 -要知道的东西太多了
Hmm.There's so much to know.
Yeah. So much we don't know.
是啊 太多东西我们都不知道
你们才刚接触
You guys are new to this.
It's like a rite of passage for all new parents
感觉不中用是所有新手父母的
必经之路
to feel inadequate.
[chuckles softly]Oh, there we go.
哦 来了
BISHOP: Hi.
嗨
Where is everybody?With Jimmy.
-其他人在哪里 -在Jimmy那里
Apparently, changing a diaper is now a three-person job.
显然 现在是三个人在换尿布
Swell. Update.
很好 有什么进展吗
手机没有什么发现
Well, no help on the cell phone.
Other than calling his attorney, Vicious used it exclusively
除了给律师打电话 Vicious只打给过几个
to call burn phones.
一次性号码
No wife or girlfriend to be found.
没有发现他妻子或者女朋友的线索
再查查这些号码
Recheck the numbers.
See if any have a Florida area code.
看是否有佛罗里达地区的号码
Boss 虽然讨厌这样子 但我还得说我不能错过
Boss, I hate to say this, but I really can't miss
明天早上去芝加哥的航班
my flight to Chicago in the morning.
McGee 不会错过的
No one's missing anything, McGee.
Once we confirm the killer, you go,
只要我们确定了凶手 你就可以走了
whether we find the mother or not.Thank you.
不论有没有找到孩子的母亲
谢谢
It shouldn't take too long. Seems pretty open-and-shut.
应该要不了太久 这看上去已经很清楚了
这不是看上去清楚 Tim
Oh, it doesn't seem open-and-shut, Tim.
It most definitely is.
是绝对清楚
Fingerprints?And blood.
-指纹对上了吗 -还有血迹
后面的是Jerome的
The latter being Jerome's,
前面的与Vicious符合 就是我们的凶手
and the former matching Vicious, our killer.
对这两个人来说 这可不是个愉快的结局
Well, not a happy ending for either party,
但至少这破案速度是我们期待的
but at least it's the quick case we were hoping for.
Kase 拿到DNA了吗
Kase, you get DNA?
DNA不符合
DNA came back negative.
-什么 -Albert 外号Vicious
What?Albert aka Vicious
肯定
is most definitely
not the baby's father,
不是孩子的亲生父亲
我们得找这孩子的父亲与母亲了
making us oh-for-two on parents right now.
好了
BISHOP: All right,
here's the little man, good as new.
这个小孩 完好如初
这可不是你的功劳 McGee
[chuckles]Yeah, no thanks to you, McGee.
Uh-oh. Nobody's smiling.
大家怎么都不笑
怎么了
What's wrong?
这是个偷来的婴儿
We're looking at a stolen baby.
Hey, wouldn't we have heard something?
我们怎么会没有收到任何消息
There had to be an Amber Alert.
这肯定会有安珀警报
【Amber Alert：安珀警报，发生儿童绑架案时，透过各种媒体向社会大众传播】
Make that three alerts, Director,
这周发出过三个警报 主任
just in the Northeast this week.
就在东北部
But none for a newborn.
但没有新生儿
I just can't believe the statistics on missing kids.
我简直无法相信失踪孩子的统计数据
I mean, they're stolen from hospitals, parking lots,
我是说 小孩子从医院 停车场
people's own homes.
自己家里被偷走
Double-check every case.
重新再查下每件案子
Start locally, work outward.
从本地开始 向外排查
I've got two cases here in the Metro area,
我找到市中心区的两桩案子
but neither matches our baby's age or description.
但都不符合这个孩子的年龄和外貌
What kind of monster would steal a baby?
什么样的恶人居然会偷孩子
The kind dead on Palmer's table.
已经躺在解剖台上的恶人
Whatever lowly, depraved person you were in life,
不论你在生活中有多么卑微堕落
here's your chance in death.
你死了也是有机会的
Where did you get that baby?
你在哪里偷来了这个孩子
Are you really expecting an answer?
你真的在等他回答吗
From beyond, maybe.
也许来自来世
A psychic message.
通灵消息
At this point, I will take what I can get.
现在 我会收集我能得到的信息
I need a word with my buddy Jerome.
我想和Jerome说说话
Yeah, you mentioned that he reminded you of someone?
你说过他让你想起了某个人
Oh, yeah. Not really, though.
也不算是
But did you happen to find anything in his clothes?
但你有没有碰巧在他衣服里找到过什么
Anything that might have fallen out, maybe?
有没有什么东西掉出来
Anything like...?
比如
Purple Heart. This box was in his duffel
紫心勋章 这个盒子在他的行李箱里
with no medal inside.
但里面没有勋章
Wow. No, I didn't find anything like that.
没有 我没找到那样的东西
Got me looking into his service record,
这让我查了他的服役记录
and turns out he did not one,
结果发现他去了中东不止一次
but three tours in the Middle East.
而是三次
Purple Heart came after an IED nearly killed him.
在一次差点杀了他的爆炸后 他得到了紫心勋章
That would explain all the old surgical scars.
那些旧手术伤疤就说得通了
After he was discharged, he battled PTSD
他退伍后 一直在与创伤后应激障碍
and a painkiller addiction for years.
和止疼药成瘾作斗争
V.A. tried to provide support, but with no living family,
退伍军人管理局试着给他提供帮助  但他没有家人
he fell off the grid entirely in '07.
他在07年的时候完全掉线了
Off the grid?Oh, homelessness.
-掉线了 -哦 无家可归
An all-too-common tale.Yeah, the numbers are pretty staggering.
不奇怪的故事了
这些人数非常惊人
You think the medal might have fallen out
你认为勋章在
when McGee was packing the duffel?
McGee在装袋他行李箱的时候掉了吗
You know, that or maybe Jerome
或者Jerome
just pawned it for cash at some point.
之前把它当了换钱
Yeah. But he kept the box.
但他留着盒子
So clearly, it meant something to him.
很明显 这对他有重要的意义
He should be buried with it.
他应当戴着它下葬
[groans] Too late to hit the V.A. center.
这个点给退伍军人管理局打电话太晚了
Yeah, we'll just have to go over there in the morning.
我们明天直接过去
Uh, "we"? Tomorrow is Christmas Eve.
我们吗 明天是平安夜
Okay, so we'll go over there early.
好的 那么我们早点去那里
Well, the medal obviously meant something to Jerome,
勋章明显对Jerome意义重大
which means something to you, so...
也就是说对你也有帮助 那么
why not"we"?
为什么我们不一起去呢
McGEE: All right, you bring the blanket around,
把毯子裹上
keep it nice and tight,
裹得紧些
and there you go, snug as a bug.
好了 温暖又舒适
He's like a little baby burrito.
像个玉米卷饼
I like burritos.
我喜欢玉米卷饼
Look how secure he looks.
看看他感觉多么安全
Like he's back in the womb.
像是回到了子宫内 去吧
There you go, buddy.GIBBS: Hey. Don't you got to get going?
嘿 你还不走吗
Uh, yeah, boss. Got an early flight
头儿 要赶最早的航班
to catch-- still got to pack.
还得打包
But, uh, I know you'll find the mother before then, so...
但我知道你会先找到他的母亲
Go, McGee. Say hi to your family.
去吧 McGee 代我向你家人问好
Merry Christmas.Merry Christmas, boss.
-圣诞快乐 -圣诞快乐 头儿
Happy holidays, guys.
大家节日快乐
See ya.Bye, McGee.
-再见 -McGee再见
What about you?
你呢
What time's your plane leave?
你的航班几点
Uh, whenever. I can book a later one.
任何时候都行 我可以订个晚点的
You know, I still think
我还是认为
Child Services is the best place for him.
儿童服务机构是最适合他的地方
BISHOP: Ooh, and we
我们
respectfully disagree.
并不太同意
I mean, where are they gonna put him, anyway?
他们会把他送到哪里去
He's already been through so much
他已经经历了这么多事
to be handed off to some stranger.
被某个陌生人偷走
Little Nicky's place is right here.
小Nicky要待的地方就在这里
Oh. Now he's Little Nicky?
现在他是小Nicky了吗
Okay, I get it, but...
行了 我明白了
he can't stay here.
但他不能呆在这里
Which one of you gonna take him home?
你们谁把他带回家
Well, your place isn't exactly, uh, baby-friendly.
你家不怎么适合小孩子
And your place is no day care center.
你家那里没有日托所
And neither one of you
你们两个都不知道
know how to take care of a baby.
怎么照顾小孩子
Nope.
不行
[chuckles]: No.
不可能
Not gonna happen. N...
I'm not doing it.
我不会这么做的
[baby fussing]
No.
不行
TORRES: Yeah, this is more like it.
对 就像这样
No. More like it would be you tending the fire
不 应该是你来生火
and me holding the baby.
我看着孩子
你什么时候在乎起了刻板的性别角色
And since when do you care about stereotypical gender roles?
[groans]
Whoa.
哇
Whew. Remind me to clean out the attic.
提醒我要清理阁楼了
You still have this.
你还留着这个
Got to hold on to what you can.
把能留的都留着
You know, it might be a better idea to set this up
把这个装在
in the spare bedroom upstairs.
楼上的空房间可能会更好
Uh, we were also thinking that
我们也这么考虑过
maybe, uh, down here could be
也许 楼下会
a little bit more cozy, plus...
更加舒服 另外
you know, the three of us can take shifts. Shifts?
我们三个可以轮流照顾他
轮流
Yeah. Like... you know, like, every few hours.
就是 每隔几小时换一次人
Yeah.
是啊
No.
不行
No shift for me.
我不来
No, I'll be in the basement.
我去地下室待着
Night.
晚安
[Bishop sighs]
What?Huh?
-怎么 -什么
You sighed.
你刚叹了口气
I didn't sigh.
我没叹气
Okay, I sighed.
好吧 我叹气了
I was just thinking about what Gibbs said
我刚才只是在想Gibbs说过的
about hanging on to what you can.
珍惜你所拥有的一切
Talking about the bassinet?
你说的是这个婴儿车吗
His daughter's bassinet.
这是他女儿的婴儿车
Mm...
嗯
his ornaments.
他的圣诞装饰
You know, Shannon and Kelly,
你知道 Shannon和Kelly
they've been gone for so many years, but...
她们已经离开好多年了 但是
给爸爸 爱你的Kelly
he keeps them right there up on the tree.
他一直在树上留着她们的卡片
Forever means forever.
永远就是永远
I almost died today, Nick.
我今天差点死掉 Nick
I'm trying not to think about it.
我尽量不去想这事儿
Yeah, you and me both.
我也是
And that baby...
那个宝宝
made it a lot easier.
让我很容易忘记这件事
But it can't help but make a person
但是那件事让人不得不
reassess things, you know?
重新审视很多事情 你知道吗
Things like...?
比如
Like what you just said.
比如你刚说的
Forever.
永远
What we hold on to, what we leave behind.
我们坚持什么 我们留下什么
And?And...
-然后呢 -然后
I don't know.
我不知道
I always thought I'd be a mom someday,
我一直觉得某一天我会当一个妈妈
but... I never really pictured myself,
但是 我从没真正想象过我自己
like, mothering, you know?
做妈妈是什么样子
[chuckles]Hmm.
嗯
Well, after today, I feel pretty much prepared for anything.
经历过今天这些事 我感觉自己已经完全准备好应对任何事了
[crying]Ay.
唉
Right on cue.
真是时候
You know, I never saw any medals.
我从没见过任何奖章
Butmaybe that nice agent who was here yesterday,
也许昨天来这里的那个不错的探员
maybe he dropped them.
把它们都丢掉了
You might want to look around Jerome's bed.
你们也许想仔细看看Jerome的床
Thanks so much. We shouldn't be long.
非常感谢 我们不会耽误很长时间
I must say, I've been having some challenges
我得说 我一直很难找到他的近亲
just trying to find his next of kin
来告知他的
to notify.Jerome didn't have any.
-死讯 -Jerome没有近亲
Parents died before he was enlisted
他的双亲在他入伍前就去世了
记录上也没有兄弟姐妹和表亲
and no siblings or cousins on record.
-你们给我省了不少麻烦 -但是如果你们需要招人
You saved me some trouble.But if you need a point person
-去参加葬礼 我很乐意... -呃不 不 不
for funeral plans, I'm here...Uh, no, no, no.
退伍军人事务部会处理好一切的
No, no, the V.A. will handle everything.
They'll come and pick up Jerome's body
圣诞节一过 他们就会过来
right after Christmas.
带走Jerome的遗体
[phone ringing]Ah. Excuse me.
啊 抱歉
你能提出去葬礼真是太贴心了
Well, that was certainly nice of you to offer.
Man's got no one else.
这个人没有亲人
I'll never understand how a guy
我永远无法理解
like Jerome could end up homeless.
一个像Jerome这样的人会沦落到无家可归
You know, some young people enlist
要知道 有些年轻人应征入伍
to escape a bad homelife or neighborhood.
是为了逃避糟糕的家庭生活或者邻居
They get some structure, some discipline,
他们在那里有组织 有纪律
only to be discharged and come back to
只是在退役之后又要回到
none of those things.
无组织无纪律的生活中
Same bad homelife, same low prospects.
依然糟糕的家庭生活 一样绝望的前景
Only for some of them, it's compounded
只不过对于他们中的某些人而言
by the emotional and physical wounds of combat.
战斗造成的心理和生理创伤更加复杂
You sure know a lot about this subject.
你对这事非常了解啊
My, uh... my dad did.
我 呃 我父亲比较了解
Wait. Was he ever homeless?
等等 他曾经无家可归过吗
No, but he always said he could have been.
不 但他总说自己本可能无家可归
Struggled himself after serving.
服役之后挣扎生活
Then he got a job with the post office and started a family.
然后他在邮局找了一份工作并组建了一个家庭
But he counseled homeless veterans on the side.
但他经常为无家可归的老兵们提供咨询
He was helping 'em get a leg up, he'd say.
他会说 他是在帮他们站起来
So that's why we're here.
所以这才是我们来这里的真正原因
Thisis something your dad would have done.
这正是你父亲会做的事
Maybe.
也许吧
Is it true what I just heard?
我听到的是真的吗
Vicious killed Jerome?
是Vicious杀害了Jerome吗
It appears to be the case, yeah.
看起来是这样的 没错
So Jerome did it.
所以Jerome确实那么做了
He went and ratted Vicious out to the cops.
他去向警察告发Vicious了
Uh, ratted him out?
呃 告发他
Jerome was kicking himself for not stopping it right away.
Jerome当时正为自己没有立即阻止他而自责
Stopping what?Whatever he saw Vicious do.
-阻止什么 -阻止Vicious正在做的事
He wouldn't say what, but Jerome told me right here in this room
他不肯说是什么事 但是Jerome就在这个房间里告诉我
he planned to go to the cops about it.
他打算去跟警察说这件事
And now he's dead.
现在他死了
Wait, wait.
等等 等等
Whatever Jerome saw,
不管Jerome看到了什么
did he happen to say where and when?
他有没有碰巧提过是什么时候在哪里发生的
SLOANE: ♪ Dashing through the snow
♪ Dashing through the snow ♪
♪ In a one-horse open sleigh
♪ In a one-horse open sleigh ♪
♪ Over the fields we go...
♪ Over the fields we go... ♪
[sighs] Jack?
Jack
Hey, what about skiing in Vermont?
嗨 怎么不去佛蒙特州滑雪了
哦 我今早犯了个错误
Oh, I made the mistake of checking in
出发前跟Vance打了个招呼
with Vance before leaving this morning.
[phone rings]One mention of a stolen baby,
他提了一下被偷走的宝宝
我觉得你们可能会比较缺人手 所以
and I thought you guys might be a little shorthanded, so...
Hey. Yeah, Palmer, what do you got?
嗨 Palmer 你有什么发现
So you came all the way back for, uh, the case or the baby?
所以你大老远回来是为了帮我们破案子还是看孩子
哦 得了 谁不爱孩子
Aw, come on. Who doesn't love a baby?
I especially love a baby
我尤其喜欢
in a safe and happy home.
让孩子待在安全幸福的家里
Yeah, which we're still no closer to finding.[baby cooing]
我们在这一点上没有任何进展
Palmer found a witness.
Palmer发现了目击证人
We need to dig up security footage
我们需要看看安南代尔城
from an all-night store in Annandale.
一个夜间商店的监控录像
TORRES: What are we digging for?
我们要找什么
Anything we can find
任何跟Vicious和
on Vicious or our victim.
我们的受害人有关的事情
[door opens]
Hey, guys.
嗨 伙计们
McGee
McGee?Couldn't sleep a wink, so, uh, booked a later flight.
一点也睡不着 所以 呃 订了个晚一点的航班
发生了什么 我以为你应该在佛蒙特州了
What happened? I thought you were supposed to be in Vermont.
Oh.
哦
Any luck, Tim?
有什么发现吗 Tim
花了些功夫 不过很幸运 安南代尔城
Well, took some doing, but fortunately, there is only one
只有一个便捷超市 你说要看停车场是吗 老大
Atlantic E-Z Mart in Annandale. You said the parking lot, boss?
That's what Palmer said. Around 3:00 in the morning.
是Palmer说的 大概凌晨3点左右
Hard to know what we're looking for exactly.
很难知道我们要看什么
[sighs heavily]
Slow it down.
放慢
Who's that?
那是谁
Do we know her?
我们认识她吗
Nope, not yet.
暂时不认识
Well, that's our guy right there.
那就是我们要找的人
That is Vicious.
那是Vicious
He's taking the baby.
他正在拿走宝宝
I'm gonna be sick.
我感觉好恶心
Here comes Jerome.
Jerome来了
Wait. What is she doing?
等等 她在干什么
McGEE: He's giving her an envelope.
他给了她一个婴儿车
And she's... she's letting him take the stroller.
然后她 她就让他把婴儿手推车推走了
Oh, my God, that baby wasn't stolen.
哦 天呐 那个宝宝不是被偷走的
McGEE: Boss, that's got to be money.
老大 那一定是钱了
He was sold.
他是被卖掉的
我无法想象那个女孩经历了什么
I cannot imagine what this girl's been through
to want to sell her baby.
以至于要卖掉自己的孩子
You got anything?
你有什么发现吗
Uh, the only prints on this stroller belong
呃 婴儿车上唯一的指纹
to Bishop and Torres, and no hits on DNA, either.
属于Bishop和Torres，DNA也没有匹配结果
Facial recognition?
面部识别呢
KASIE: No matches yet.
暂时还没结果
What's that about?Oh, that? That's nothing.
-那是什么 -哦 那没什么
那不是没什么 她是想
It's not nothing. She's trying
给Jerome找一个紫心勋章 Gibbs探员
to find a Purple Heart, Agent Gibbs, for Jerome.
You can buy one online for,
你可以花大概50块
like, 50 bucks,
从网上买一个
但是过年期间的物流要花好几个星期才能到
but delivery this time of year takes weeks.
为什么Jerome会需要一个紫心勋章
Why does Jerome need a Purple Heart?
因为他得过一个 然后弄丢了
Because he earned it, and lost it.
[phone ringing]
Yeah. Yeah.
是啊 好
Leon, I'm on my way.
Leon 我马上来
What?
什么
You're such a sweet boy.
你真是个可爱的小伙子
Well, so much for your ski trip.
你的滑雪之旅就这么泡汤了
McGee 芝加哥之旅什么情况
And McGee, what about Chicago?
What can we say, Leon?
我们能说什么呢 Leon
We're here for the same reason you are.
我们跟你过来的原因是一样的
不太可能 我是来泼冷水的
Doubtful. I'm pulling the plug.
What? This is what
-什么 -这应该是
儿童保护机构的业务范围 他们名字上写着呢
Child Protective Services does. It's right there in their title.
但是 主任
不 我不会再浪费我们的任何时间
But, Director...No, I'm not gonna waste any more of our time,
our resources, and all of our holidays
任何人力和任何假期
trying to do what they do best.
去做他们最擅长的工作
你看过视频之后 可能就不会这么说了
I'm not sure you'd say that if you saw the video.
The mother was sobbing, Director.
那个母亲在哭泣 主任
一定有更多的隐情
There has to be more to the story.
她还有隐情
Certainly herstory.
嗨
BISHOP: Hey.
所以 没有目击者
So, no witnesses,
而且我们查过了便利店和周围的邻居
and we all but papered the walls of the convenience store
就差在墙上贴寻人启事了 没有人认识她
and the neighborhood around it.Nobody knows her.
How's my Little Nicky?
我的小Nicky怎样了
Hmm. Looks more like a Logan to me.
嗯 我说他看起来更适合叫Logan
巧了 我之前想的也是Logan
BISHOP: Hey! I was thinking Logan, too.
-是吗 -是的 或者叫Cody
Yeah.Yeah, or like a Cody.
但是 我想他看起来更像叫Luke的
See, I'm thinking he looks more like a Luke.
哦 又一个源自星战的名字 是吗
Oh, another Star Warsname, huh?
我相信 Logan是金刚狼
Well, I believe, uh, Logan is Wolverine.
叫他超人的名字怎么样 Kent Clark
How about, uh, Superman? Kent? Clark?
好吧 我们可能还没找到
VANCE: Well, we may not have found
孩子的母亲 Gibbs 但是这宝宝倒是一点儿也不缺
the mom yet, Gibbs, but this baby certainly has no shortage
of aunts and uncles.
叔叔们和阿姨们
你好 超人
Hey, Superman.
-我们还是叫他超人吧 -Albert是个更好的名字
Let's just call him Superman.Albert's a better name.
我想说的是 这事没必要把Gibbs牵涉进来
I'm just saying, there was no need to involve Gibbs.
当然有必要
There is always a need.
瞧  Kasie 如果你想帮助Jerome 你就该
Look, if you want to help Jerome, Kasie, you got
-允许其他人帮助你 -我是让你来帮助我
to let other people help you.I let youhelp me.
但我不是Gibbs
I'm not Gibbs.
你父亲肯定也不是独自一人帮助这么多
Surely your dad didn't help all these homeless vets
all by himself, did he?
无家可归的老兵们的 对吗
不 我不知道
No. I don't know.
只是别把我父亲扯进来
Look, just leave my dad out of this.
又是这样 每次我提到你的父亲
There you go again. Every time I bring up your dad,
-你就转移话题 -不 我没有
you change the subject.No, I don't.
Now find a face already.
赶紧找到匹配的面孔吧
It was him, wasn't it?
就是他 不是吗
Who Jerome reminded you of.
Jerome让你想起来的
It was your dad.
就是你的父亲
You got all weird when
你看到Jerome的尸体的时候
you saw Jerome's body, the same weird
就变得很奇怪 跟你听到别人
that you got at any mention of your dad.
提起你父亲时一样的那种奇怪
Look, I...
你看 我
I'm sorry.
我很抱歉
I overstepped there. I didn't mean to...
我越界了 我并不想
No. No, you're right.
不 不 你是对的
I get weird.
我变得奇怪了
[sighs heavily]
Jerome reminded me of the first dead body I ever saw.
Jerome让我想到了我见过的第一具尸体
It was your father.
那是你父亲
About the same age, Navy tattoo.
也是那样的年纪 海军纹身
[sighs]
让我想到我们一起过的最后一个圣诞
It just reminded me of our last Christmas together.
在打开礼物的过程中
In the middle of opening presents,
我提到关于完成研究生学业
I mentioned having second thoughts
about finishing grad school, and he was... he was not happy.
我有其他的想法 这让他 他不是很高兴
[sniffles]
你知道 他总是说只要我提高自己
You know, he always said I had a knack
if I would just apply myself, and...
我就能掌握窍门 而且
oh, needless to say, it ruined the day,
噢 不用多说 那天就那么不欢而散了
之后的每一天都过得不安生
and most every day after that,
直到他离世的那天
right up till the day he died.
-那是什么时候 -在那一个月之后 毫无征兆
When was that?[crying]: A month later, out of nowhere.
在他送邮件的时候心脏病突发
Just had a heart attack on his mail route.
你知道吗 急救人员说
[sniffles] You know, the medics said
他还没倒地前就已经死了
that he was dead before he even hit the ground.
妈妈无法承受去确认尸体的痛苦 所以我去了
Mom couldn't bear to I.D. the body, so I did.
Kasie, I'm so sorry.
Kasie 我很抱歉
You know, the day after that, I went back to grad school,
你知道吗 第二天 我就回研究生学院了
and I busted my butt, and he was right.
然后尽全力学习 而且他是对的
I had a knack.
我掌握了诀窍
一周之内 我就开始和Ducky一起工作 而且
And within a week, I started working with Ducky, and...
天哪 我从心底知道
man, I knew in my heart
that I was on the right track after all.
我终于走上了正轨
Wait. All of this was a year ago?
等一下 这些都是一年前的事情吗
Last Christmas, yeah. [sniffles]
去年圣诞 是的
Well, there you go. Kasie,
你看 就是这样了 Kasie
that's why you don't want to go home.
这就是为什么你不想回家
不 我 我还有工作要忙 而且我
No, I-I... I have work to do, and I...
No. No, you don't.
不 不 你没有
And your mom and your sister--
而且你的妈妈和姐姐
they're-they're not going on any cruise, are they?
她们 她们没有在什么游轮上 是吗
I just... I know it's gonna be a rough Christmas.
我只是 我知道这个圣诞不会好过
[computer chirps]
There we go. Got a hit.
你看 找到匹配了
啊
[sniffles] Uh,
Tanya Jacobs, 17.
Tanya Jacobs 17岁
因为贩卖毒品进过三次少管所
Three trips to juvie for drug offenses.
是的 Palmer 你发现什么了
GIBBS: Yeah, Palmer. What do you got?
We're sure it's the same Tanya?
我们能确定是同一个Tanya吗
她的身份证和缓刑号昨天用来登记入住了
Her I.D. and probation number were used to check in yesterday.
她知道我们在这里 管理员肯定联系过她了
She knows we're here.Manager must have called.
Tanya Jacobs! NCIS!
Tanya Jacobs 我们是NCIS
Tanya! Please let me go! Let me go!
-Tany -请让我走 放开我
It's okay. Tanya, it's okay.
没关系的 Tanya 没事的
一点也不好 别来烦我 好吗
It's not okay. Leave me alone, please!
Hey, hey, we just want to talk.
嗨 嘿 我们只是想来谈谈
这不是我的 我发誓 我发誓
It's not mine, I swear. I swear.
It's okay.
没关系的
[crying]
你这是毒品正好起效了 对吧 Tanya
You pretty high right now, Tanya?
I'm not high at all.
一点也没有
I've been clean for months.
我几个月没沾过了
There anybody we can call?
我们能联系谁吗
Parents?Yeah. Yeah, right.
-父母 -对 对 想得美
No. They kicked me out as soon as I got pregnant.
不 我一怀孕他们就把我扫地出门了
Then my boyfriend skipped town.
然后我的男朋友不告而别了
That's when the adoption agency hooked me up with Pete and Judy.
就是那时领养机构帮我和Pete与Judy联系上了
Last name?They don't tell you that.
-他们姓什么 -他们不会告诉这个的
They were nice people, though.
但他们是很好的人
So nice.
特别好的人
They helped pay for my rehab and my medical care,
他们出钱帮我戒毒还承担了我的医保
all just for a chance to adopt my baby.
只为有一个机会能领养我的孩子
When did Vicious come along?
Vicious什么时候出现的
Right before I delivered.
就在我将要生产前
I used to be a customer before I got clean.
我戒毒前曾经是他的顾客
When he saw me knocked up, he offered me ten grand cash.
当他看到我肚子大了 他给了我一万的现金
More money than I had ever seen.
我从来没见过那么多钱
So I lied.
所以我撒谎了
I told Pete and Judy that I wanted to keep the baby.
我告诉Pete和Judy我想留下自己的孩子
And I felt bad for breaking their hearts,
让他们伤心我感觉很不好
but adoption agencies--
但是那些领养机构
once the baby comes, they don't pay you.
宝宝一旦出生了他们就不再付钱了
而且我拿到钱的那一刻就知道我错了
And I knew it was wrong the second I took the envelope.
But opportunities like that, they don't...
但那样的机会 可不是
they don't come around every... maybe ever.
不是常有的 可能不会再有
I thought I'd be okay,
我以为我会没事的
but then I found out that Vicious was dead,
但之后我发现Vicious死了
and-and-and... and now I don't even know where my baby is.
而且 而且 现在我甚至不知道我的孩子在哪里
Tanya, we have him.
Tanya 他在我们那里
You do?
真的吗
Yes. He's safe.
是的 他很安全
[exhales]: Wha...
这
[laughs]
What's the name of the agency?
领养机构的名称是什么
[exhales]
This changes everything.
这改变了所有事情
Why-why does it change everything?
为什么 为什么这改变了所有事情
I mean, maybe this is a sign.
我是说 这可能是个暗示
我一直 一直在这里呆坐着
I've been... I've been sitting here,
and I've been thinking maybe...
而且我一直在想或许
maybe if I would've just kept my baby,
或许如果我一开始就留下我的孩子
我就能给所有人省去不少麻烦了
then I would've saved everybody from all this trouble.
No, no, no, no.Why not?
-不 不 不 不 -为什么不
我现在有钱了
I've got money now.
I could get us a place.
我能给我们找个地方
A nice one.
一个不错的地方
我是说 或许这就是 这就是我第二次机会
I mean, maybe this-this could be my second chance.
嗨 Tanya 你现在最好不要有孩子
Hey, Tanya, y-your best chance is without a baby right now.
而且你宝宝最好的机会就是和那对养父母在一起
And your baby's best chance is with those adoptive parents.
[crying]
This opportunity...
这样的机会
doesn't come around much.
不是经常有的
You have come this far,
你已经走到这一步了
but you could go so much further,
你还可以走得更远
and so could your baby.
你的宝宝也一样
If you let him go.
只要你放弃他
You seem so sure. How do you know?
你看起来很确定 你怎么会知道
Because I know. All right?
因为我确实知道 好吧
我们一生总会有后悔的事情
We all end up with regrets in our life,
but one thing you will never regret
但是一定不会后悔的是
让你的孩子有一个更好的生活
is giving your baby a better life.
这比什么都重要 我就是知道
More than anything else, I know that.
And I'll help you get the support you need
而且我会给你支持帮助你
重新开始 改变生活
to get clean and turn your life around.
I promise.
我保证
-好吗 好的 -好的 我会的 谢谢
Okay? Okay.Okay, I will. Thanks.
Tanya，Vicious对这个宝宝有什么计划吗
Tanya... what did Vicious have planned for the baby?
问题就在这里 这不止是钱的事情
Well, that's just the thing. It wasn't all about the money.
It was to Vicious.
对Vicious来说就是钱
Who was he selling the baby to?
他想把宝宝卖给谁
他说有个很不错的家庭正等着呢
He said he had a nice home lined up.
Rich people.
有钱人家
好像是医生还是律师什么的
Like, a-a doctor or a lawyer or something.
律师
Lawyer.
让我给你省点时间吧 Gibbs探员
Let me save you some time, Agent Gibbs.
这已经是最糟糕的一次平安夜了
It's already been the worst Christmas Eve ever.
Yeah. How?
是吗 怎么了
我妻子已经发现我 为了实现
My wife figured out what kind of strings I was pulling
领养而走后门了
to make this adoption happen.
你把付钱给一个毒贩子让他给你
You call paying a drug dealer to buy you a baby
买个孩子叫做 走后门
"pulling strings"?
Stupid, I know.
太蠢了 我知道
-噢 这可不只是愚蠢了 -在我帮Albert
Oh, it is way more than stupid.After I got Albert
拿到了辩诉交易之后 他问我他能做什么报答
the plea deal, he said if there was anything he could do.
他说任何事都行
And he meant anything.
所以你就说 来个宝宝怎么样
So you said, "How about a baby?"
那时我们第三次领养申请刚被驳回
Our third adoption had just fallen through,
我们都崩溃了
and we were crushed.
Albert said
Albert说只要
for 25 grand, he would find us
两万五 他就能帮我们找来
一个健康的愿意生育的母亲
a healthy and willing birth mother.
两万五千美元
$25,000.I was desperate to give my wife a family.
我太想给我妻子一个完整的家庭了
Never expecting anyone was gonna die over it.
从来没想过会因为这个出人命
嗨
JIMMY: Hey.
-听说好消息了吗 -是的
Hear the good news?Yeah.
Uh, great. I mean, bittersweet, but at least we can find
啊 太好了 我是说 苦乐参半 但至少我们
the original adoptive parents now.I'm sorry.
能找到原来的养父母了
抱歉 你是要说什么吗
Am I interrupting something?Oh, no. Just...
哦 没有 只是
just deleting a bunch of spam. You headed home?
只是在删除一些垃圾邮件 你要回家了吗
Yeah, I just wanted to, uh, come by.
是的 我只是想 来这看看
Drop off a little something.Jimmy, why?
留下一点东西 Jimmy 为什么
You didn't have to. I didn't get you anything.
你不必这么做的 我也没给你什么
Yes, you did. Trust me.
你已经给了 相信我
Do I open it now or...?That would be the idea, yeah.
-我是现在打开还是 -我就是这么打算的 是的
Just o-open it.Yeah. Okay. [laughs]
-你就打开吧 -好吧 好的
It's not Jerome's,
这个不是Jerome的
but it's-it's someone's.
但这个是某人的
Someone who doesn't need it anymore, I guess.
某个不再需要它的人 我想
Who?I don't know.
-谁 -我不知道
But that is why you involve Gibbs.
但这就是你去找Gibbs的原因
He knows people.
他认识一些人
Thank you, Jimmy.
谢谢你 Jimmy
Merry Christmas.
圣诞快乐
Oh, and Kasie?
噢 Kasie
I'm a big believer in fate.
我非常相信命运
I know there's nothing good that can be said
我知道你父亲的死亡
about your dad passing away,
不能说是什么好事
but if nothing else, it led you here.
但抛开别的不说 它引导你到了这里
To us.
遇上了我们
I sometimes think maybe my dad gave me a little...
我有时就想 可能我在天堂的父亲
shove from above.
给了我一个机会
Well, we're all glad that he did.
我们都很高兴他这么做了
Hey.
嗨
We've got the hang of this now.[fusses]
我们已经找到窍门了
Yeah. He's looking stylish, too. Aren't you, little Cody?
没错 他看起来很时髦 不是吗 小Cody
What? Cody?
什么 Cody
Consider that my Christmas present to you.
就把这当做我给你的圣诞礼物吧
McGEE: Great news.
好消息
The agency tracked down Tanya's adoptive parents.
领养机构找到了Tanya的养父母
Pete and Judy Shaw
住在费尔法克斯的Pete和
of Fairfax. They're only 20 minutes away.
Judy Shaw夫妇 离这里只有20分钟的路程
Oh, that's... that's great.Mm-hmm.
-噢 这真是 真是太好了 -是的
I got a plane to catch.
我还要赶飞机
May the Force be with you, little Han Solo.
愿原力与你同在 小小Han Solo
【注:Han Solo，即星球大战里的千年隼号船长汉·索罗】
Really good job, you guys.
干得漂亮 你们两位
Thanks.
谢谢
Okay, then, little guy. Here we go.
好啦 那么 小伙子 就是这样了
Yeah, so, uh...
是的 那么
we tell Gibbs now, right?
我们现在告诉Gibbs 对吗
Mm-hmm.Mm-hmm.
-是的 -没错
You know, they say, "You can't take it with you."
你们知道 俗话说 死不带去
But this? [sighs]
但是这个
This, Jerome, you are...
这个 Jerome 你
most definitely taking with you.
你一定要带在身边
Or as my father used to say...
正如我父亲曾经说过的
"No greater love than this,
一个人为了朋友献出生命
that one should lay down his life for his friends."
没有比这更伟大的爱了
WOMAN: Hey, baby. What's up? You okay?
嘿 亲爱的 怎么了 你还好吗
No, Mom, I'm fine, really. I just, um...
没事 妈妈 我很好 真的 只是
I actually finished that work faster than I thought
实际上我完成工作的时间比预料的要早
and was thinking maybe I could still catch a flight home?
我想我能不能按原计划搭飞机回家
Oh! We'd love to have you here, sweetheart.
噢 我们欢迎你来这里 宝贝
Hey, Jack.
嘿 Jack
Hey.
嗨
You still coming?
你还来吗
Are you kidding me?
你开玩笑吗
I wouldn't miss it for the world.
我一定不会错过的
Special Agent Gibbs?
你是特别探员Gibbs吗
Ms. Miles.
Miles女士
叫我Lydia 没错 我是领养机构的人
Lydia, yes. From the adoption agency.
我和你们的McGee探员通过电话
I spoke with your Agent McGee on the phone.Special Agent Sloane.
我是特别探员Sloane
Thank you so much for arranging this on such short notice.
谢谢你这么快就把这些事安排妥当了
Of course. We were overjoyed.
当然 我们万分高兴
We worked it all out with Tanya.
我们和Tanya那边协调好了
她对你们两位评价非常高
She spoke very highly of you both.
I take it the child is with you?
我想你们把孩子带来了吧
Absolutely.Great.
-当然 -太好了
All right, here we are. Hi.Hi.
好吧 我们到了 你好 你好
非常感谢你们的到来 谢谢
Thank you so much for coming. Thank you. Yeah.
And there he is.Oh.
-孩子在这里 -噢
Wonderful. Well, I'll just take him from here.
太好了 好吧 现在由我接手吧
No.
不
Sorry. It's just we'd like to...
抱歉 只是我们想
deliver him ourselves, if that's okay.
亲自把他送走 如果可以的话
实际上 这可能更好 我告诉过Shaws夫妇
Actually, that might be better. I told the Shaws I was coming
but didn't want to get their hopes up
我要去 但你们到来之前我不想
before you got here.
让他们满怀希望
They've been let down before.
他们之前就被辜负过
Yes, we know.
是的 我们知道
Why don't I just, uh, go on
这样好不好 我进去告诉
and break the good news while you wait at the door?
他们好消息 同时你们在门口等着
Great.
太好了
This is a nice neighborhood.
这里是个很好的社区
Good schools. I checked.
旁边的学校不错 我查过了
That's good. That's good to know.Mm-hmm. Yeah.
-那很好 很高兴知道这一点 -嗯 对
Good schools. That's important.
好学校 很重要
Hey, you two.
嗨 你们两个
You should get over there.
你们应该去那边了
Right. Okay.
是的 好的
Bye, buddy.
再见 孩子
[clears throat]
Are you okay? Got it?
你还好吗 接好了吗
Ooh.
噢
Oh, how adorable.
噢 太可爱了
[Bishop chuckles]Congratulations.
祝贺你们
Thank you.[chuckles]: Thank you.
-谢谢 -谢谢
Come on.
走吧
That was weird.
那可有点奇怪
Yeah. Just kind of came out.
没错 自然而然就说出来了
[both chuckle]
[sighs] Okay.
好的
Hey, uh, hold on.
嗨 呃 等一下
You did good.
你做的很好
Yeah. You did, too.
是的 你也一样
We both did.
我们都做的不错
And you did good, too, bud.
你也不错 兄弟
Yeah.
是的
You...
你
会到一个很好的家庭
are going to a great home.
You're gonna love it there.
你会喜欢那里的
Absolutely.
一定会
Oh, wow.All right, that's not even fair, buddy.
-噢 哇 -好吧 这可不公平 兄弟
[exhales] Okay.
好吧
[Torres sighs]
BISHOP: Let's go.
我们走
Pete and Judy,
Pete还有Judy
这就是我和你们说过的探员们
these are the agents I was telling you about.
他们一直在照顾你们的孩子
They've been taking care of your baby.
Our baby?
我们的孩子
Yeah, your baby.PETE: This is, uh...
-是的 你们的孩子 -这真是
It's a miracle, right?
这是个奇迹 对吗
这必然是个奇迹
It's got to be a miracle.
Sure feels like it.
感觉就是这样
Does he have a name?
他有名字吗
That's up to you.
那就由你们决定了
JUDY: Thank you.
谢谢
噢 太感谢了
[chuckles]: Oh.Thank you so much.
Congratulations.
祝贺你们
接着
[sighs]Here.
[chuckles]
圣诞快乐 Gibbs
Merry Christmas, Gibbs.
Merry Christmas to you, Jack.
圣诞快乐 Jack
You still going skiing?
你还要去滑雪吗
It's a little late now.
现在有点晚了
Why? You got a better plan?
为什么 你有更好的计划吗
我在想你分发的礼物酒
I was just thinking about that gift bottle you gave out.
-肯塔基州最好的 -噢
Kentucky's finest. Small batch.Oh.
就一小批
我想打开了 你来吗
I want to crack that. You in?
[laughs]
Captioning sponsored by CBS
Captioned by Media Access Group at WGBH access.wgbh.org